SANDEEP VENKATA PUNUGU

Solution Architect

9373078019

SUMMARY

As a seasoned Solution Architect with a strong background in designing and implementing complex systems, I am excited to transition into the field of Machine Learning. My extensive experience in architecting solutions for a wide range of industries, combined with a deep understanding of cloud computing and data engineering, positions me as a valuable candidate for this role.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Solution Architect/Pega Lead System Architect

R2Tech LLC

2023 - Present

Virgnia

Solution Architect/Pega Lead System Architect

iTech US Inc

2016 - 2022

Virginia

Sr Software Engineer/Pega Systems Architect

iTech US Inc

= 2009 - 2016

Virginia

Software Engineer/Pega Systems Architect

Cognizant Technology Solutions

2006 - 2009

Multiple

STRENGTHS



Architectural Expertise

With a proven track record in designing scalable and resilient systems, I bring a wealth of knowledge in building infrastructure that can support the demands of machine learning workloads. This includes optimizing cloudbased architectures and implementing DevOps practices for ML deployment.



Strong Communication

Effective communication is essential in ensuring alignment between technical teams and business stakeholders. My experience in delivering clear, concise explanations of technical concepts and decisions is an asset in this regard.



Cross-functional Collaboration

Throughout my career, I have worked closely with engineers, and business stakeholders to bridge the gap between business requirements and technical solutions.



Problem-solving and Adaptability

My ability to solve complex technical challenges and adapt to rapidly evolving technology trends allows me to navigate the ever-changing landscape of machine learning effectively.



Lifelong Learning

I am deeply committed to continuous learning and staying current with the latest developments in machine learning, including advancements in models, tools, and best practices.

MACHINE LEARNING EXPERTISE



Data Exploration/Analysis, preprocessing using AWS Kinesis, Glue, and other services. Build and deploy ML models using AWS Sagemaker, tuning hyperparameters using Sagemaker services.



GCP

Exploratory analysis using BigQuery, Vertex Al. Build and deploy models using BigQuery ML, and Vertex Al. Build data pipelines using Apache Beam/Dataflow.



Kaggle Competitions

Participated in multiple competitions in NLP, deep learning, classification, and regression using TensorFlow, keras, scikit-learn, and other tools

ALDIE, VA

EDUCATION

Masters in Computer Engineering Wright State University

= 2003 - 2005

SKILLS

Machine Learning

Classification Regression NLP **Computer Vision Data Analysis Data Visualization** Model Development **Data Preprocessing Statistical Analysis ML Ops Big Data Deep Learning**

Programming Languages/Packages

Python	Pandas	NumPy	Tensorflow
pySpark	pyTorch	Scikit-Le	arn
Matplotlib	Seaborn	ı —	

Tools

AWS	GCP	Github	Jupyter Notebook		
Docker	Kub	ernetes	Spark	Linux	
Othor To	ر ما مرام	nio o			

Other Technologies

Pega PKP	C	Java	J	avascri	pτ

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Solutions Architect -Associate
- AWS Machine Learning Professional
- Pega PRPC Senior Systems Architect 8.x
- Pega PRPC Systems Architect

TRAINING / COURSES

Machine Learning Specialization - Coursera

Generative AI with Large Language Models -Coursera

PROJECTS

AEOB VTC

🗰 2022 - Present

Locatio

Architected the application in Pega which determines the validity, compatibility edits for Medical Claims via a REST service

CCAE(Pharmacy VTC)

= 2021 - 2022

VA

Architected the application in Pega which determines validity, compatibility edits for Pharmacy Claims via a REST service

Workflow Management

= 2016 - 2021

VA

Architected a workflow solution using Pega PRPC which helps Plans(Healthcare companies) manage, allocate work to its processors, and also automate claims processing

Medicare Audit Remediation - Edits

= 2015 - 2015

VA

Designed and developed the SOAP service using Pega PRPC to process Medicare OPR edits as part of the claims adjudication system

ICD 10 Compliance Implementation and BP Failsafe Removal

= 2010 - 2015

VA

Developed the SOAP service in Pega PRPC to replace legacy module in Mainframe which determines benefit service for claims

Benefits Administration

= 2009 - 2010

♀ VA

Designed and developed a GUI application in Pega PRPC to replace the legacy java application which is used to CRUD codes, code groups, services, products

eWatson SPA

= 2007 - 2009

AW C

Short summary of your work